Register of the Constantin W. Boldyreff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1940-1995
  - Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz Rossiiskikh Solidaristov (The National Alliance of Russian Solidarists) (NTS), 1944-1989
    - Fundraising letters, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 23:15-20)
    - Meetings materials, agenda, speeches, and correspondence, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 24:1-5)
    - "Kadet" prospectus,", 1973-1986 (Box-folder 24:6)
    - NTS statement to the United Nations by Petr Arkad'evich Stolypin, 1975 (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Soviet Dissidents materials, 1964-1978
    Includes statements, writings, photographs, and correpondence.
    - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 24:8-9)
      Includes Boldyreff's correspondence and writings on Solzhenitsyn.
    - "The Trial of the Four," photographs, clippings, and statements, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 24:10-12)
    - Petro G. Grigirenko, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 24:13)
      Includes autobiography, family photograph, statements, list of scientific works, and Zinaida M. Grigorenko's "Open Letter to the World Federation of Mental Health."
    - Alexander Yesenin-Volpin, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 24:14)
      Includes statement, supportive letter signed by soviet scientists, Hearings Before the Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security, translated by Boldyreff.
    - Meeting of Americans of Russian descent in front of the United Nations, New York, 1971 December 12 (Box-folder 24:15)
    - Avraham Shifrin's Hearings Before the Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security, translated by Boldyreff, 1973 (Box-folder 24:16)
  - Trip to the Middle East, Germany, and England, report, correspondence, and receipts, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 25:1-5)
- Writings by Others, 1943-1997
  - Akaeist sviatomu angelu, 1963 (Box-folder 25:6)
  - Dvinov, Boris, "Politics of the Russian Emigration,", 1955 (Box-folder 25:7)
  - Episkop Serafim, Palomnichestvo iz N'iu Iorka v Sviatuiu Zemliu, 1957 (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Filippov, Boris, Polustanki and Hepogod', 1960-1962 (Box-folder 25:9)
  - Fisher, Anthony, Must History Repeat Itself?, 1974 (Box-folder 25:10)
  - Govorukhin, Stanislav, Velikaia krminal'naia revoliutsiia, 1993 (Box 25:11)
  - Haskell, Edward, "Bibliography on Unified Science and Related Subjects,", 1974 (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Leibert, Julius A., Kingsbery, Emily, Behind Bars, 1965 (Box-folder 26:1)
  - Lyons, Eugene, Our Secret Allies, and The Underground Moscow Fears Most, 1954, 1968 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - Martin, David, Patriot or Traitor: The Case of General Mihailovich, 1978 (Box-folder 26:3)
  - Petelchuk, Paul, "The National Aliance of Russian Solidarists,", 1970 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - Semler, Helen, Moscow Rediscovered, a Guide to the City and Russian Civilization, and Moskva obretennaia, 1992, 1997 (Box-folder 26:5-6)
  - Shubart, Walter, "Evropa i dusha Vostoka,", 1943 (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Stewart-Smith, D. G., The Defeat of Communism, 1964 (Box-folder 27:2)
  - Trohan, Walter, "The Cost of Re-arming Europe under the North Atlantic Pact," broadcast, 1949 (Box-folder 27:3)
  - Tryshnovich, Y., "Freedom must be fought for,", 1954 (Box-folder 27:4)
- Printed Matter, 1942-1974
  - The Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 as Amended and the Rules and Regulations Prescribed by the Attorney General, 1942 (Box-folder 27:5)
  - Georgetown University School of Foreign Service brochures, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 27:6)
  - Khronika zashchity prav v SSSR, vypusk 10, 1974 (Box-folder 27:7)
- Clippings, 1921-1995 (Box-folder 27:8-9)
  Collection of clipped newspaper articles on topics relating to research subjects.
- Oversize Materials, 1878-2001 (Box 28)
  - Russian Imperial medals, 1878-1896
    Three medals: "Commemorative medal of the Russo-Turkish war 1877-1878," "Commemorating the Reign of Alexander III 1881-1894," and "In memory of coronation of Nikolay II, 1896."
  - Appreciation letters to Boldyreff from refugees of Mönchehof DP camp, 1945
  - Family photographs, 1957-1961
  - Semler, Peter, "A Memoir,", 2001
- Sound Recordings, circa 1985 (Box 29)
  - Antonina Boldyreff talks regarding C. Boldyreff, compact sound cassette
  - 1/4 -inch sound tape reels
    Titles and numbers given by the donor.
    - No. 81 "Vokrug da okolo"
    - No. 82 "V chem privlekatel'nost' materializma, solidarizma"
    - No. 83 "Pochemy N.T.S. vprave zvat' na bor'bu"
    - No. 84 "Zhuravlinaia pesnia"
    - No. 89 "Zazhitochnost' krest'ianstva-osnova blagosostoianiia strany"
    - No. 90 "Padaiushchego podtolkni"
    - No. 254 "Golos svobodnogo Kitaia"
    - No. 255 "Primer dostoinyĭ podrazhaniia"
    - No. 369 "Chertovy kacheli"
    - No. 370 "Za svobodu slova"
    - No. 371 "Ubrat' gniiushchie trupy"
    - No. 372 "Dun'koĭ byla-Dun'koĭ i ostalas'"
    - No. 373 "Gotovit'sia k ukhodu Khrushcheva"
    - No. 374 "Ko dniu roshdeniia Khrushcheva"
    - No. 375 "Kto vrag?"
    - No. 376 "U sebia doma"
    - No. 390 "Nakanune"
    - No. 391 "Proshchaĭte"
    - No. 392 "Zashchishchaĭte svobodu veroispovedaniia"
    - No. 393 "O tom i o sem"